[MUSIC]
[음악]
So what we're gonna do next
다음으로
is #Let's show what our
#예측 보여주기
predictions look like.
라고 적습니다
Now I talked about using GraphLab Canvas as a way to visualize data, but
GraphLab Canvas를 데이터 시각화에 쓴다고 말씀드렸는데
you can also use other tools out there to visualize; other python tools.
다른 파이썬 도구도 있습니다
So just as a simple demonstration of that, I'm going to import one search tool.
간단한 설명을 위해 도구 하나를 import 하겠습니다
It's a pretty commonly used one.
꽤 널리 사용되는 도구지요
It's called mot plot lib.
matplotlib라고 합니다
And so, and from there I'm gonna
pyplot을 쓰면 그래프를 쉽게
input something called pipe plot which allows you to do some plotting in Python.
그릴 수 있습니다
And I'm gonna refer to it as PLT.
plt라고 호칭하죠
So when you're doing the importing Python, if you type import myplotlib.pyplot,
파이썬에서 import할 때 팩키지의 일부인
is a particular piece of the package, and I write as plt.
matplotlib.pyplot을 plt라고 줄여서 import합니다
Now I don't have to write this whole thing matlab_lib.pyplot blah blah blah,
그러면 matplotlib.pyplot이라고 다 적을 필요 없이
I just write plt.
간단히 plt라고만 해도 됩니다
That's why we use the as command.
as 명령어를 사용하는 이유죠
So I'm gonna import it, and one little trick I'm gonna do, just like you did with
import한 다음 요령을 좀 부릴건데
Canvas to make sure it prints inside the notebook I'm gonna do it here too.
Canvas에서 했던 것처럼 노트북에 직접 출력합니다
So you put this percent, and
퍼센트 기호를 붙이고
you say, matplotlib inline.
matplotlib inline이라 적습니다
So that just plots it on the notebook itself.
이러면 노트북에 그래프가 그려지게 되죠
So let's hit Enter.
엔터를 칩니다
We've imported it, and now I'm going to actually build
import를 했으니 처음으로
a map plot lib plot for the results, for the initial results.
그래프를 그려보겠습니다
So we're gonna plot plt.plot.
plt.plot로 그립니다
And there's a function here.
함수가 있죠
And I'm gonna plot my test data in two ways.
테스트 데이터를 두 가지 방법으로 그려보죠
So it's interesting, can plot two multiple plots on top of each other with MyPlot 11.
matplotlib으로 두 그래프를 서로 겹치게 그릴 수 있죠
We're just gonna do that together.
바로 해보겠습니다
So I'm gonna take my test data and in my test data I'm
테스트 데이터를 전용면적 x축에
gonna plot on the x-axis the square feet of living space.
그리겠습니다
And in the y-axis for my test data, I'm going to plot the price.
테스트 데이터에서 y축은 가격이 되죠
So, this is kind of similar to the plot we did above, the scatter plot.
전에 했던 것과 비슷한 산점도가 됩니다
And I'm gonna refer to each one of these points as test points.
이 점들을 테스트 점(포인트)이라 부르겠습니다
I'm gonna draw them as a dot.
점으로 그리죠
So, that's what this little dot here does.
여기 이 작은 점을 입력하면 그렇게 됩니다
However, I'm also going to plot one more thing.
하나 더 그려보죠
So I'm going to plot two things on the same plot.
하나의 그래프에 두 개를 그릴 겁니다
Actually, so I'm missing a comma up here.
여기 쉼표를 빠뜨렸네요
So in addition to plotting the test data, let's plot our predictions.
테스트 데이터와 함께 예측을 그립시다
So again, on the x-axis is going to be the square feet of living space,
x축은 아까와 같이 전용면적이 되고
but on the y-axis, I'm going to plot something else.
y축은 좀 다른 걸 그리죠
I'm going to plot what my model predicted for each one of those houses.
모델이 각 주택에 대해 예측한 걸 그립니다
So remember we built this square foot model and
평수 모델을 만들 때
it has many functions associated with it.
관련 함수가 많이 있었지요
If you go down, one of those functions it has is called the predict function.
내려보면 예측 함수란 것도 있습니다
And the predict function, you can give it a bunch of data's input and
예측 함수에 데이터 입력을 주면
it's gonna output and estimates our column of data with the predictions for
각 입력에 대해 예측 데이터를
each one of these input elements.
배열이나 열 형식으로 출력합니다
So, I'm giving you the test data and I'm going to draw it as a dash.
테스트 데이터를 입력해서 대시 기호로 나타내 보죠
Now, before I execute this line,
이 줄을 실행하기 전에
just take a moment to imagine what this plot is going to look like.
그래프가 어떻게 생길지 생각해 봅시다
So, the top line says plot living space through the price test data with dots.
윗 줄은 전용면적 대 가격을 점으로 그리라고 합니다
It's going to look very similar to the scatterplot that we drew before.
전에 그린 산점도와 비슷하게 되겠죠
And the second line says plot
두 번째 줄은
the input houses living with the prediction with a dash.
입력 주택의 거실에 대한 예측을 대시 기호로 그리라고 돼있습니다
And now remember this was a simple linear regression model with a single variable so
간단한 회귀 모델에 단일 변수이니
all we have is a single variable and
강의에서 다뤘듯 단일 변수와
as we covered in the lectures, we just plotted a single line.
직선 하나만 그리면 됩니다
And we'll see that execute and here we are.
실행시켜보면 이렇게 되죠
So the blue dots here are the test data for the houses,
파란 점들은 주택의 테스트 데이터이고
while the green line corresponds to the predicted house values.
녹색 선은 예측 주택 가치입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]